The longest time in the world is the hesitation between thought and action.
It can actually be forever.
You can hesitate for one second to get started on something, a workout, a project, a task,
something that you know you should do.
You can hesitate for one second.
That one second of hesitation also turns into five seconds and then ten seconds and
then ten minutes.
And in just like that, you drifted into the eternity zone.
One second became an eternity because something that was going to happen is now never going
to happen.
Ever.
Why is that because you hesitated?
So don't take that chance instead, take action.
A body in motion tends to stay in motion.
A body at rest tends to stay at rest.
You've had enough damn rest.
You've got to get to the point in your life where you decide I have had it.
I'm tired of being a loser.
I got tired of losing.
I got tired of coming up short.
I got tired.
I want to move to the nicest neighborhood.
I want to fly first class.
I want to go to Hawaii.
I made a decision, enough is enough.
It's show time.
In order for you to go from one level to the next level, in order for any woman to transition,
for any man to transition, the thing that they want must be greater than the thing they
currently have.
Humans do not transition to another level when they comfortable with the level that they're
on.
You only go to another level when you say, enough is enough.
I want you to live the life you were meant to live.
You hear me?
Not the life that was given to you.
You deserve to see what your life would look like if you gave a hundred and twenty percent.
And what I need you to do is I need you to look at yourself and the men say, come on,
stop playing.
I deserve to see what my life would look like if I gave a hundred and twenty percent.
That's a lie, I'm old.
You got to get to a place where you start executing.
Making a freaking plan is the easy part.
And you have to understand if you don't execute on the plan, if you don't get up in the
morning when you're feeling tired, scared, if you don't execute, you're not just cheating
yourself, dude.
You're cheating your family.
You're cheating your employees.
You're cheating your team, whatever you're a part of.
It's bigger than you, man.
And guess what?
I had to get up even though it was hard and I had to take ownership of my life, take
ownership of my time, take ownership of my day.
And those of you who messed up why?
Because you don't understand, think, act, eat, rest.
We talked about a schedule.
I realized that my strength is in my routine.
Why?
Because I'm not as strong as I thought I was.
I'm not as intelligent as I thought I was.
And my routine is what I do every day, repeatedly.
The DNA of your successes in your routine, you're not as deep as you think you are.
You've got a fun routine.
I'm getting up at three and stick with it.
I'm getting up at five and stick with it.
Yeah, I have 365 days where I'm a bad dad too.
But I'm trying to tell you, the strength is in the routine.
Find a routine and stick with it.
No one dreamin' it.
Dreamin' is over.
I mean specifics.
What are you doin' on Monday?
What are you doin' on Tuesday?
What are you doin' on Wednesday?
You need to be very specific.
It's time to put yo' eastern together of your puzzle.
Nobody gave me this iron dish.
Life wasn't a crystal stare for me.
Didn't nobody give me a network?
I earned a network.
I worked my way to the NBA.
I worked my way to the NFL.
Everybody say, he, how did you crack the code?
I climbed it my way through the code.
That's how I cracked it.
I got up every day at three.
I don't care what the economy is doing.
I don't care who the president is.
Nobody helped me to get here.
I had to get up.
I had to go to class.
I had to read.
I had to study.
I had to write.
I understood that the dream is real,
but the lifestyle is realer.
It doesn't matter what everybody else is doing.
Stay predictable.
Stay consistent.
And the reason why many of you are not getting it
is because you're not consistent.
You start and you stop.
You get pumped up.
You start strong.
And then somewhere in the middle, you quit.
You have a little success,
but you don't experience exponential growth
because you're not consistent.
You gotta be persistent.
You gotta be locked in.
You can't score more watch.
So many of you score more watch it.
Every time you do something,
you're looking up to see the score.
You stop and work in to look at yourself.
You're not grinding.
You glaring.
You should be grinding it.
You're looking at the score.
The score is what it is.
The score ain't about the change
because you looked at it.
Keep playing the game.
Keep grinding.
Keep marking.
And that other stuff will take care of itself.
I'm challenging you to get from where you are.
I'm challenging you to stop settling.
I'm challenging you to stop accepting
the life that was given to you.
I'm challenging you to give 120%.
If you don't do what you say you don't do,
be what you say you don't be,
you're gonna have to lie on me out.
You're a gazelle.
You're gonna come up short.
You're not always gonna get what you want outta life.
You're a gazelle.
You don't have an average experience.
You were soon, I knew you were lying, More.
You were teacher, I knew you were lying, More.
You were not your manure, I knew you were lying, More.
You try to lose weight, lie, More.
You can't do nothing significant in gazelle, More.
Nothing.
Nothing impressive happens in gazelle, More.
Nothing happening, run, More.
Give up, More.
Quit, More.
Scared, More.
Seared from, More.
Nothing happens.
Everything happening, lie, More.
Like I'm coming to get you.
You constantly trade on this opportunity.
You don't worry about tomorrow.
You constantly trade on this opportunity
with all your might, with all your soul, with all your heart.
You focus on this and tomorrow we'll take care of itself.